const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following features, according to Light's criteria, is suggestive of exudative effusion?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural fluid LDH : serum LDH ratio > 0.6","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural fluid protein : serum protein ratio < 0.5","bool":false},{"option":"Protein content of fluid < 30 g/L","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid LDH < 2/3 of upper limit of normal serum LDH","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid glucose is higher than serum glucose","bool":false}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which one of the following drugs is not used for productive cough?","answers":[{"option":"Vasaka","bool":false},{"option":"Guaiacol","bool":false},{"option":"Bromhexine","bool":false},{"option":"Benzonatate","bool":true},{"option":"Acetyl cystine","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the extra volume of air that can be inspired over and above the normal tidal volume, when the person inspires with full force, called?","answers":[{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory reserve volume","bool":true},{"option":"Alveolar volume","bool":false},{"option":"Tidal volume","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"In which of the following diseases does the total lung capacity decrease?","answers":[{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":true}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is the major air pollutant of indoor smoke?","answers":[{"option":"Carbon monoxide","bool":true},{"option":"Nitrous oxide","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Sulphur dioxide","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrogen dioxide","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Ziehl–Neelsen staining is an important tool in the diagnosis of Mycobacterium tuberculosis. Its cell wall resists decolorization with acid due to the presence of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Mycolic acid","bool":true},{"option":"Teichoic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Capsule","bool":false},{"option":"Lipids","bool":false},{"option":"Protein channels","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 20-year-old male presents with fever and cough for 3 weeks. After 2 weeks, he develops a headache and an altered level of consciousness. On examination, his temperature is 101°F. CNS examination reveals right-sided weakness with signs of meningeal irritation. CSF shows increased proteins, decreased glucose, and increased WBCs with predominant lymphocytes. What is the likely possibility?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculous meningitis (TBM)","bool":true},{"option":"Bacterial meningitis","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebral malaria","bool":false},{"option":"Cerebrovascular accident","bool":false},{"option":"Viral encephalitis","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 38-year-old office worker presents with a high-grade fever and productive cough. On examination, he has a temperature of 102.8°F, and a bronchial breath sound on the left upper chest. Which organism for pneumonia is more common in people working in air-conditioned offices?","answers":[{"option":"Legionella pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Vestibular toxicity is associated with which of the following drugs?","answers":[{"option":"Ethionamide","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Rifabutin","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":true},{"option":"Cycloserine","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 35-year-old female brings her pleural fluid analysis report, which shows the exudative nature of pleural fluid with a high amylase level. She gives a history of upper abdominal pain and vomiting in the recent past. She also had pulmonary tuberculosis 10 years ago. She has now developed pleural effusion. What is the most likely cause of her current condition?","answers":[{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute cholecystitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute pancreatitis","bool":true},{"option":"Malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Systemic lupus erythematosus","bool":false}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Caplan syndrome is associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Silica","bool":true},{"option":"Barium sulfate","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":false},{"option":"Beryllium","bool":false},{"option":"Bagasse","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"An adult woman presented to an ophthalmologist with decreased visual acuity and color blindness for green. She has been on anti-tuberculous therapy (ATT) for 1 month. Her fundoscopy was normal. The ophthalmologist asked her to stop which of the following drugs considering the cause of her symptoms?","answers":[{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":true},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Radiation hazard most commonly leads to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Genetic changes and malformations","bool":true},{"option":"Leukemia only","bool":false},{"option":"Death due to chronic liver failure","bool":false},{"option":"Shortening of life always","bool":false},{"option":"Coronary artery diseases","bool":false}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"One of the deleterious effects of cigarette smoking is the functional deficiency of the alpha-1-antitrypsin enzyme. Which substance present in smoke has this action?","answers":[{"option":"Nicotine","bool":false},{"option":"Oxidant","bool":true},{"option":"Antioxidant","bool":false},{"option":"Carbon monoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Nitrogen dioxide","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"An HIV-positive male presents with fever and cough with hemoptysis for the past 2 weeks. His sputum is acid-fast bacillus (AFB) smear-positive. He is started on antitubercular treatment (ATT) but even after 4 months, there is no response. The doctor suspects multi-drug resistance. Which is the usual/common resistant pattern?","answers":[{"option":"Resistance to isoniazid (INH)","bool":false},{"option":"Resistance to all first-line drugs","bool":false},{"option":"Resistance to rifampicin","bool":false},{"option":"Resistance to isoniazid and rifampicin","bool":true},{"option":"Resistance to any 2 first-line drugs","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A young female presented with a low-grade fever and dry cough for the past 6 months. On examination, there were bilateral fine crepitations. Investigations showed increased serum calcium levels and bilateral hilar lymphadenopathy on chest X-ray. What is the most probable diagnosis for this lady?","answers":[{"option":"Lung cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial pneumonitis","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is not associated with sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cardiac arrhythmias","bool":false},{"option":"Hypocalcemia","bool":true},{"option":"Erythema nodosum","bool":false},{"option":"Cranial nerve palsies","bool":false},{"option":"Arthralgia","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the possible genetic factor of sarcoidosis?","answers":[{"option":"11:22 translocation","bool":false},{"option":"Associated with a certain HLA haplotype","bool":true},{"option":"Telomerase shortening","bool":false},{"option":"Deletion of chromosome IIp","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of transforming growth factor-beta 1 (TGF-β1)","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A medicolegal doctor is called to perform a post-mortem examination. He gives an incision starting from one inch below the symphysis menti up to symphysis pubis without cutting the umbilicus. What is this incision called?","answers":[{"option":"Modified Y-shaped- incision","bool":false},{"option":"Y-shaped incision","bool":false},{"option":"I-shaped incision","bool":true},{"option":"T-shaped incision","bool":false},{"option":"Cruciate incision","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"The arterial blood gas (ABG) analysis of a patient shows pH=7.31, PCO₂=24 mmHg, and HCO₃=12 mmol/L. What is the most likely metabolic disturbance?","answers":[{"option":"Partially compensated combined acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Compensated metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Partially compensated metabolic acidosis with respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Compensated combined acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Partially compensated metabolic acidosis","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A post-mortem examination of the lung of an elderly male shows destruction of smooth muscle and elastic tissue, chronic necrotizing inflammation, and dilation of bronchi and bronchioles. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":true},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 24-year-old asthmatic lady becomes pregnant. On examination, she has severe bilateral bronchospasm. Which of the following complications might she develop due to uncontrolled asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Maternal eclampsia","bool":true},{"option":"Fetal cardiac defects","bool":false},{"option":"Spina bifida","bool":false},{"option":"Intrauterine growth retardation","bool":false},{"option":"Post date delivery","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A patient with tuberculosis develops bright orange-red-urine and calls his physician in panic. The patient has no other urinary tract symptoms. Which of the following medication is most likely to produce this side effect?","answers":[{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":true},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxine","bool":false}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 25-year-old patient presents with sudden onset of flu-like symptoms followed by high-grade fever and chest pain. Chest X-ray shows bilateral cavitary pneumonia. Which of the following would be the most likely causative organism?","answers":[{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":true},{"option":"Streptococcus viridans","bool":false},{"option":"Klebsiella","bool":false},{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 35-year-old female presents to the outpatient department with progressive shortness of breath and dry cough. She has a history of red eyes as well. Chest X-Ray shows bilateral hilar lymphadenopathy, widespread pulmonary lines, and honeycombing. Which of the following is the best diagnostic test?","answers":[{"option":"Lung biopsy","bool":true},{"option":"Serum ACE level","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary function test","bool":false},{"option":"Chest high-resolution CT (HRCT)","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoalveolar lavage","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 45-year-old female presents to the outpatient department with progressive shortness of breath and dry cough. She has a history of joint pain and red eyes as well. Chest X-ray shows bilateral hilar lymphadenopathy, widespread pulmonary lines, and honeycombing. Which of the following would the patient be suffering from?","answers":[{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptogenic fibrosing alveolitis","bool":false}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 65-year-old known case of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) and bronchiectasis is admitted to the intensive care unit with fever and shortness of breath. The patient is put on a mechanical ventilator. He then develops bronchopneumonia. What is the suitable choice of antibiotic to be used?","answers":[{"option":"Ciprofloxacillin and aminoglycoside","bool":false},{"option":"Penicillin and aminoglycoside","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftazidime and ciprofloxacin","bool":true},{"option":"None of these","bool":false},{"option":"Ceftazidime and aminoglycoside","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 70-year-old male presents with high-grade fever and chest pain. Examination shows bronchial breathing affecting the right lower part suggesting consolidation. Which of the following will be used for severity assessment?","answers":[{"option":"ABG with PaO2 < 8K Pa","bool":false},{"option":"Age > 65","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral lower lobe involvement","bool":false},{"option":"ABG with SaO2 < 92%","bool":false},{"option":"CURB-65","bool":true}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 12-year-old boy came to the emergency department with complaints of abrupt onset of high fever with shaking chills, productive cough, and mucopurulent sputum. On gram stain, numerous pus cells with gram-positive lancet-shaped diplococci were observed. Which of the following is the most likely organism?","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Hemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Moraxella catarrhalis","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 2-year-old girl is brought to the emergency room with complaints of high-grade fever, noisy breathing, and drooling for 1 day. On examination, temperature = 104°F and respiratory rate = 60/min. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Epiglottitis","bool":true},{"option":"Peritonsillar abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Spasmodic croup","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial tracheitis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute laryngeotracheobronchtis","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 26-year-old housewife develops a high-grade fever, cough with purulent sputum, and pleuritic type of chest pain. The lady was previously in a good state of health. What is the most probable diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute exacerbation of chronic bronchitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 26-year-old woman comes to the hospital due to dyspnea on mild exertion. The patient has no other medical conditions or addictions and is not currently on any medication. Her mother had similar symptoms and died at the age of 42 years. After an extensive workup, a lung biopsy is performed which shows medial hypertrophy, intimal fibrosis, and decreased intraluminal diameter of small branches of the pulmonary artery. Which of the following best describes this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary disease","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 4-year-old boy has a 1-month history of recurrent cough with wheezing. There is no history of previous similar complaints and no family history of asthma or tuberculosis. Examination shows enlarged cervical nodes and bronchi. Chest X-Ray shows air trapping on the right side during inspiration. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Nodal tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Reactive airway disease","bool":false},{"option":"Foreign body aspiration","bool":true},{"option":"Gastro esophageal reflux","bool":false},{"option":"Right middle lobe syndrome","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 40-year-old known asthmatic patient is brought to the emergency room due to severe exacerbation of asthma. He must be given oxygen and frequent administration of corticosteroid with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Cromolyn","bool":false},{"option":"Ipratropium","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":true},{"option":"Zileuton","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 3-year-old boy is brought with complaints of difficulty in breathing, noisy harsh sounds produced during inspiration, and high-grade fever for 2 days. What will be the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Laryngitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bacterial tracheitis","bool":false},{"option":"Epiglottitis","bool":true},{"option":"Foreign body inhalation","bool":false},{"option":"Acute laryngotracheobronchitis (croup)","bool":false}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 6-year-old male child is brought to the emergency room because of recurrent wheezing. He is on inhaled steroids. His mother gives a history that he has daytime symptoms> 2/week and nighttime symptoms > 2/months. On spirometry, his FEV is > 80% with a PEF variability of 30%. He gets diagnosed with asthma. What is the classification of severity of asthma in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Severe persistent asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Mild intermittent asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Mild persistent asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Cough variant asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Moderate persistent asthma","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 6-year-old child has a sudden onset of dyspnea with wheezing. On physical examination, he is afebrile but has absent breath sounds on the right. His temperature = 37 °C, pulse \r\n= 82/minute, respiratory rate = 28/minute, and blood pressure = 100/60 mm Hg. An arterial blood gas measurement shows pO2 = 95 mm Hg, pCO2 = 25 mm Hg, and pH = 7.55. Following the administration of 100% FiO2 by nasal canula, a repeat measurement shows pO2 = 95 mm Hg, pCO2 = 25 mm Hg, and pH = 7.55. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Paraseptal emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboembolism","bool":false},{"option":"Foreign body aspiration","bool":true},{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial asthma","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 65-year-old man comes to the emergency department due to the sudden onset of shortness of breath and chest pain that started a few hours ago. He has been immobilized due to left leg pain and calf swelling for the past 30 days. The patient has no other medical condition, no addiction, and takes no medication. His temperature = 36 °C, blood pressure = 80/60, pulse = 112 min, respiratory rate = 30/min. Chest X-Ray reveals a wedge shaped infiltrate. Which of the following best describes this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Chronic obstructive pulmonary diease","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":true},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary hypertension","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A middle-aged male presents with a two-week history of severe shortness of breath and fever. On examination, he is cyanosed with bilateral coarse crepitations all over the chest. Chest X-Ray shows bilateral lung infiltrates, with O2 saturation of 88% on room air. What is the next best investigation as part of management?","answers":[{"option":"Complete blood count","bool":false},{"option":"ESR and CRP","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoscopy","bool":false},{"option":"High resolution CT","bool":true},{"option":"Arterial blood gases","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A patient is taking some kind of RNA synthesis inhibitor for the treatment of a mycobacterium infection. They return back to the clinic extremely worried about recent events. They claim their urine, saliva, sweat, tears, and feces are all reddish-orange in color. What drug is the patient most likely to be taking?","answers":[{"option":"Rifampin","bool":true},{"option":"Cycloserine","bool":false},{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazide","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 20-year-old thin, tall boy presented to the emergency room with sudden onset of cough, severe shortness of breath, and chest pain. He recently arrived from the USA after a 16-hour flight. Immediate chest X-Ray was advised with the suspicion of pneumothorax. Which chest examination finding best reveals pneumothorax?","answers":[{"option":"Dull percussion note on the affected side","bool":false},{"option":"Increased chest movements on the affected side","bool":false},{"option":"Resonant percussion note on the affected side","bool":false},{"option":"Hyper-resonant percussion note on the affected side","bool":true},{"option":"Increased breath sounds on auscultation on the affected side","bool":false}]},{"id":41,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 20-year-old female presents with shortness of breath. On auscultation, bilateral rhonchi are audible. Spirometry shows an obstructive pattern with complete reversibility after bronchoconstriction. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Coal worker pneumoconiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis","bool":false},{"option":"COPD","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial asthma","bool":true}]},{"id":42,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 28-year-old female came with acute shortness of breath for one day. She is experiencing night symptoms for the past 2 months. What is the cause of raised diffusion capacity for carbon monoxide (DLCO) in pulmonary function tests?","answers":[{"option":"Obstructive sleep apnea","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":true},{"option":"Interstitial lung disease","bool":false},{"option":"Cardiac failure","bool":false}]},{"id":43,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 45-year-old male presents in the emergency department with shortness of breath, insidious in onset, and progressive with dry cough. On examination, there is cyanosis, clubbing, and end-inspiratory respiratory crepitation in bilateral lung fields. Which of the following investigation is most appropriate to establish a diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Chest high-resolution computed tomography (HRCT)","bool":true},{"option":"Lung biopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary function test","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-Ray","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoalveolar lavage","bool":false}]},{"id":44,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 50-year-old male patient presents to the outpatient clinic with shortness of breath which is gradual in onset along with dry cough for the last 5 years. On examination, there is the clubbing of fingers and bilateral basal end respiratory crackles are audible. Chest X-Ray shows bilateral lower lobe subpleural reticular shadowing. What is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Rheumatoid lung","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Hypersensitivity pneumonitis","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphangitis carcinomatosis","bool":false}]},{"id":45,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 70-year-old male patient, a heavy smoker, previously diagnosed case of COPD, has presented with cough, hemoptysis, low-grade fever, significant weight loss, and anorexia. X-ray chest reveals a large, left-sided pleural effusion. Pleural fluid analysis is done which is suggestive of exudative pleural effusion, according to Light's criteria. According to Light's criteria, exudate is likely if which of the following criteria has been met?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural fluid LDH: serum LDH ratio<0.3","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid protein: serum protein ratio <0.5","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid LDH: serum LDH ratio<0.6","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural fluid protein: serum protein ratio >0.5","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural fluid LDH < two thirds of the upper limit of normal serum LDH","bool":false}]},{"id":46,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"An adult male brought his chest X-Ray film having findings highly suggestive of post-primary tuberculosis. Which of the following radiological findings is consistent with that?","answers":[{"option":"Small pleural effusion","bool":false},{"option":"Gohn's focus","bool":false},{"option":"Miliary mottling","bool":false},{"option":"Hilar lymphadenopathy","bool":false},{"option":"Apical patchy shadowing","bool":true}]},{"id":47,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"An elderly female is admitted to the intensive care unit (ICU) for acute respiratory distress syndrome on the 4th day of total hip replacement for a fracture of the neck of the femur. Which of the following is the cause of acute respiratory distress syndrome in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Thromboembolism","bool":false},{"option":"Disseminated intravascular coagulation","bool":false},{"option":"Infection","bool":false},{"option":"Fat embolism","bool":true},{"option":"Hemorrhage","bool":false}]},{"id":48,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Caplan syndrome consists of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Asbestosis and tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Silicosis and tuberculosis","bool":false},{"option":"Berriliosis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis  and rheumatoid arthritis","bool":true},{"option":"Byssinosis and rheumatoid arthritis","bool":false}]},{"id":49,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Clinical signs and symptoms of pulmonary embolism may mimic myocardial infarction. Which of the following is the most correct method of diagnosing pulmonary embolism?","answers":[{"option":"ECG","bool":false},{"option":"Chest X-ray","bool":false},{"option":"Venography","bool":false},{"option":"Radio isotope perfusion pulmonary scintigraphy","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary arteriography","bool":true}]},{"id":50,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Clinically, chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) include which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Emphysema and asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis and emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis and emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Emphysema and bronchiolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma and bronchiectasis","bool":false}]},{"id":51,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"An asthmatic female patient recovering from myocardial infarction is on several\r\nmedications per day, including aspirin. She complains of large bruises on her arms and\r\nlegs. Her laboratory reports show elevated alanine transaminase (ALT). Which of the following is most likely responsible for the increase in liver enzymes?","answers":[{"option":"Heparin","bool":false},{"option":"Zafirlukast","bool":false},{"option":"Zileuton","bool":true},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false},{"option":"Aspirin","bool":false}]},{"id":52,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is the mechanism of action of cromolyn?","answers":[{"option":"Inhibition of phosphodiesterase","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of delayed chloride channels","bool":false},{"option":"Blockage of muscarinic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Activation of beta-adrenergic receptors","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of mast cell mediators release","bool":true}]},{"id":53,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Syndrome of inappropriate antidiuretic hormone secretion (SIADH) and ectopic adrenocorticotropic hormone (ACTH) secretion are paraneoplastic syndromes. These are associated with which type of bronchogenic carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false}]},{"id":54,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following subtype of lung cancer is most commonly found in females?","answers":[{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoids","bool":false}]},{"id":55,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Hypercalcemia is the paraneoplastic syndrome associated with which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell cancer","bool":true},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma of lung","bool":false}]},{"id":56,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"If pulmonary function test shows FEV1/FVC ratio less than 0.70 with increased total lung capacity (TLC), then the interpretation would be:","answers":[{"option":"Restrictive pattern","bool":false},{"option":"Normal","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive pattern","bool":true},{"option":"Non-specific reductions in FEV1 and FVC","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed pattern","bool":false}]},{"id":57,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"In arterial blood gases, low pH and high CO2 are seen in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Compensatory metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false}]},{"id":58,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"In tuberculosis, macrophages play an important role in antigen recognition and processing. They activate TH-1 cells through the production of which one of the important cytokines given below?","answers":[{"option":"IL-6","bool":false},{"option":"TNF","bool":false},{"option":"Defensins","bool":false},{"option":"IL-12","bool":true},{"option":"INF- Ɣ","bool":false}]},{"id":59,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Inhaled allergens in atopic asthma elicit TH2-dominated response IgE production and recruitment of which of the following cells?","answers":[{"option":"Dendritic cells","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":false},{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Plasma cells","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":true}]},{"id":60,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Inhaled salbutamol is useful in bronchial asthma due to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Aborting/terminating asthma attacks","bool":true},{"option":"Status asthmaticus","bool":false},{"option":"Round the clock prophylaxis of asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Reduces inflammation","bool":false},{"option":"Suppresses hyper-reactivity","bool":false}]},{"id":61,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the interpretation of the following spirometry results; FEV1=3.35L (Patient's value); FVC=5.22 L (Patient's value), and FEV1/FVC ratio=0.64?","answers":[{"option":"Non-specific reductions in FEV1 and FVC","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive pattern","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed pattern","bool":false},{"option":"Normal","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive pattern","bool":true}]},{"id":62,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Lung cancers may be associated with paraneoplastic syndromes. Cushing syndrome develops as a paraneoplastic syndrome due to the production of which of the following hormones?","answers":[{"option":"Calcitonin","bool":false},{"option":"Anti diuretic hormone","bool":false},{"option":"Gonadotropins","bool":false},{"option":"Adrenocorticotropic hormone","bool":true},{"option":"Parathormone","bool":false}]},{"id":63,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 55-year-old patient with chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is admitted with a complaint of increased shortness of breath, fever and cough. He was treated with antibiotics, bronchodilators and oxygen. On discharge, his resting SaO2 was 80%. Which of the following is the only drug therapy known to cause improvement in the natural history?","answers":[{"option":"Oxygen therapy","bool":false},{"option":"Inhaled bronchodilators","bool":true},{"option":"Corticosteroids","bool":false},{"option":"Theophylline","bool":false},{"option":"Smoking cessation","bool":false}]},{"id":64,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"In which of the following conditions, Tardieu spots are not seen?","answers":[{"option":"Drowning","bool":true},{"option":"Traumatic asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Strangulation","bool":false},{"option":"Overlaying","bool":false},{"option":"Lynching","bool":false}]},{"id":65,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"In case of suicidal death, an investigation conducted by friends and relatives of the deceased for collecting information and knowledge about mental status in order to justify the suicide is called:","answers":[{"option":"Death investigation","bool":false},{"option":"Medical autopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Psychological autopsy","bool":true},{"option":"Police autopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Forensic autopsy","bool":false}]},{"id":66,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following medium is used to grow Mycobacterium tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Löwenstein-Jensen medium","bool":true},{"option":"Triple sugar iron test","bool":false},{"option":"Blood agar","bool":false},{"option":"McConkeys Agar","bool":false},{"option":"Luria broth","bool":false}]},{"id":67,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"The most common association of pneumothorax is:","answers":[{"option":"Adenocarcinoma of the lung","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchiolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchiolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Mesothelioma","bool":false}]},{"id":68,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis resides in which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Neutrophils","bool":false},{"option":"Eosinophils","bool":false},{"option":"Basophils","bool":false},{"option":"Lymphocytes","bool":false},{"option":"Macrophages","bool":true}]},{"id":69,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"On the 11th day of operation of adenocarcinoma of the prostate, a 70-year-old man suddenly became extremely dyspneic and diaphoretic, with chest pain, palpitations, and a feeling of panic. Which of the following postoperative pulmonary complications is most likely to develop?","answers":[{"option":"Pulmonary edema","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse alveolar damage","bool":false},{"option":"Atelectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Thromboembolus","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural effusion","bool":false}]},{"id":70,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A convict charged with murder was sentenced with judicial hanging by the court of law. The cause of death in judicial hanging is?","answers":[{"option":"Separation of medulla oblongata from spinal cord","bool":false},{"option":"Vasovagal shock","bool":false},{"option":"Fracture and dislocation of 2nd cervical vertebrae","bool":true},{"option":"Congestive cardiac failure","bool":false},{"option":"Asphyxia due to compression of neck","bool":false}]},{"id":71,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 4-year-old boy is brought to you with complaints of fever and cough, persistent for the past 6 weeks, and has lost his weight in this period. On examination, of the chest, crepitations and a wheeze are audible on the right side of the chest. Labs show hemoglobin (Hb) of 9 gm/dl, erythrocyte sedimentation rate (ESR) of 60 mm/hr, and induration in Mycobacterium tuberculin (MT) test is 11 mm. How will you treat?","answers":[{"option":"6 months of antituberculous therapy","bool":true},{"option":"Broad spectrum antibiotic","bool":false},{"option":"Broad spectrum antibiotic with antipyretic","bool":false},{"option":"Antipyretic with antiallergy for 6 months","bool":false},{"option":"12 months of antituberculous therapy","bool":false}]},{"id":72,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is a key component of photochemical smog?","answers":[{"option":"Ozone at ground level","bool":true},{"option":"Ozone layer in upper atmosphere","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocarbons","bool":false},{"option":"Particulate matter","bool":false},{"option":"Biological pollutants","bool":false}]},{"id":73,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Pleural plaque is the most common manifestation of exposure to which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Coal","bool":false},{"option":"Radiation","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos","bool":true},{"option":"Silica","bool":false},{"option":"Beryllium","bool":false}]},{"id":74,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Regarding laryngeotracheobronchitis, the most frequently observed radiological finding is:","answers":[{"option":"Normal","bool":false},{"option":"Ragged tracheal border","bool":false},{"option":"Thickened nasopharyngeal space","bool":false},{"option":"Steeple sign","bool":true},{"option":"Thumb sign at epiglottis","bool":false}]},{"id":75,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Regarding occupational health, genetic changes are caused by:","answers":[{"option":"Silica","bool":false},{"option":"Poor lighting","bool":false},{"option":"Ingestion of mercury","bool":false},{"option":"Radioactive radiations","bool":true},{"option":"Noise","bool":false}]},{"id":76,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Regarding the morphology of sarcoidosis, which of the following is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Central necrosis is common","bool":false},{"option":"Only the lung shows the classic granulomas","bool":false},{"option":"Asteroid bodies enclosed within giant cells are present","bool":true},{"option":"Schaumann bodies are pathognomonic for sarcoid","bool":false},{"option":"Lymph node involvement is rare","bool":false}]},{"id":77,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Rifampin is not indicated in which of the following conditions?","answers":[{"option":"Plaque","bool":true},{"option":"Endocarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Leprosy","bool":false},{"option":"Hemophilus influenzae","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus osteomyelitis","bool":false}]},{"id":78,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Secondary mycobacterial infection should always be an important consideration in HIV-positive patients who present with pulmonary disease. Which of the following is the most common causative organism of this condition?","answers":[{"option":"M. leprae","bool":false},{"option":"M. kansasi","bool":false},{"option":"M. tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"M. scrofulaceum","bool":false},{"option":"M. avium complex","bool":false}]},{"id":79,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is a long-acting β2-adrenergic agonist?","answers":[{"option":"Terbutaline","bool":false},{"option":"Salmeterol","bool":true},{"option":"Albuterol","bool":false},{"option":"Metaproterenol","bool":false},{"option":"Pirbuterol","bool":false}]},{"id":80,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs is neither a bronchodilator nor an anti-inflammatory but has antihistaminic and mast cell stabilizing activity?","answers":[{"option":"Beclomethasone dipropionate","bool":false},{"option":"Ketotifen","bool":true},{"option":"Ipratropium","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorpheniramine","bool":false},{"option":"Sodium cromoglycate","bool":false}]},{"id":81,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs blocks the 5-lipoxygenase enzyme and inhibits the synthesis of leukotriene?","answers":[{"option":"Montelukast","bool":false},{"option":"Zileuton","bool":true},{"option":"Zafirlukast","bool":false},{"option":"Azelastine","bool":false},{"option":"Omalizumab","bool":false}]},{"id":82,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is the most serious adverse event associated with ethambutol?","answers":[{"option":"Hepatitis","bool":false},{"option":"Bone marrow suppression","bool":false},{"option":"Optic neuritis","bool":true},{"option":"Psychotic reaction","bool":false},{"option":"Nephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":83,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Smoking is associated with which of the following subtypes of emphysema?","answers":[{"option":"Distal acinar","bool":false},{"option":"Centriacinar","bool":true},{"option":"Paraseptal acinar","bool":false},{"option":"Septal acinar","bool":false},{"option":"Panacinar","bool":false}]},{"id":84,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Some of the pulmonary disorders are characterized by irreversible enlargement of air spaces distal to terminal bronchioles accompanied by destruction of their walls and without any obvious fibrosis. Which of the following conditions best characterizes the above statement?","answers":[{"option":"Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchitis","bool":false}]},{"id":85,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Spirometry is a clinical test used to assess the severity of diffuse pulmonary diseases that could be obstructive or restrictive. In which one of the following conditions is there a proportionate decrease in total lung capacity and forced expiratory volume in 1 sec (FEV1/FCV = normal)?","answers":[{"option":"Bronchiolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Idiopathic pulmonary fibrosis","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchial asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":false}]},{"id":86,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the amount of air a person can breathe in beginning at the normal expiratory level and distending the lungs to the maximum amount?","answers":[{"option":"Functional residual capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory capacity","bool":true},{"option":"Total lung capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Vital capacity","bool":false}]},{"id":87,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"The DNA damage due to radicals formed as a result of radiation is an example of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Splitting of chemical bonds","bool":false},{"option":"Accidental damage","bool":false},{"option":"Indirect damage","bool":true},{"option":"Direct damage","bool":false},{"option":"Threshold level damage","bool":false}]},{"id":88,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the extra volume of air that can be expired above the tidal volume, upon full expiration, called?","answers":[{"option":"Inspiratory reserve volume","bool":false},{"option":"Residual volume","bool":false},{"option":"Tidal volume","bool":false},{"option":"Alveolar volume","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory reserve volume","bool":true}]},{"id":89,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of these is a life-saving drug given parenterally in severe status asthmaticus that will act by inhibiting phospholipase A2?","answers":[{"option":"Metaproterenol","bool":false},{"option":"Aminophylline","bool":false},{"option":"Epinephrine","bool":false},{"option":"Salbutamol","bool":false},{"option":"Prednisone","bool":true}]},{"id":90,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is the most important cause of panacinar (panlobular) emphysema?","answers":[{"option":"Occupational dust","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha 1 antitrypsin deficiency","bool":true},{"option":"Cigarette smoking","bool":false},{"option":"Air pollution","bool":false},{"option":"Infection","bool":false}]},{"id":91,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"The type of asphyxia that is associated with anesthesia and surgical maneuvers is termed as:","answers":[{"option":"Mechanical asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Clinical asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Iatrogenic asphyxia","bool":true},{"option":"Pathological asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Toxic asphyxia","bool":false}]},{"id":92,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"According to the Integrated Management of Neonatal and Childhood Illnesses (IMNCI), tuberculosis vaccine is given:","answers":[{"option":"At birth intradermally on left thigh","bool":false},{"option":"At birth intradermally over right deltoid region","bool":true},{"option":"At 6 weeks of age along with hep B vaccine","bool":false},{"option":"At 6 weeks of age intradermally on left deltoid","bool":false},{"option":"At 9 months of age on left thigh","bool":false}]},{"id":93,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A medico-legal doctor is performing the autopsy for the opening of the skull during post-mortem in a newborn baby. How should the incision be done?","answers":[{"option":"Over the top of the head from right ear to the left ear","bool":false},{"option":"Cutting from mastoid to mastoid","bool":false},{"option":"Opening of sagittal + coronal sutures","bool":true},{"option":"Cutting along sagittal sutures","bool":false},{"option":"Making a circular cut","bool":false}]},{"id":94,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"The most important difference between a forensic autopsy and a pathological autopsy is that in forensic autopsy:","answers":[{"option":"All cavities are opened even if injury is not found","bool":false},{"option":"Cause of death is usually not known but has to be determined","bool":false},{"option":"It is a valid documentary evidence in the court of law","bool":true},{"option":"Done in cases of unnatural sudden or suspicious deaths","bool":false},{"option":"External findings are of vital importance","bool":false}]},{"id":95,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the main advantage of R. Virchow's technique of autopsy?","answers":[{"option":"Spread of infection (HIV, HCV) can be limited","bool":false},{"option":"Body can be made available to relatives in 30 minutes","bool":false},{"option":"Each organ can be studied in detail","bool":true},{"option":"Preservation of vascular supply in pathological lesions","bool":false},{"option":"Preservation of anatomico-pathologic relationship","bool":false}]},{"id":96,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"If the cause of death can not be determined even after a thorough post mortem examination, toxicological analysis and histopathological examination, what is the autopsy called?","answers":[{"option":"Incorrect autopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Negative autopsy","bool":true},{"option":"Failure in autopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Unusual autopsy","bool":false},{"option":"Virtual autopsy","bool":false}]},{"id":97,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What does the common radiological finding in the case of epiglottitis show?","answers":[{"option":"X-ray chest shows bilateral hilar infiltration with shifting of trachea toward left side","bool":false},{"option":"X-ray neck AP-view reveals \" steeple sign\"","bool":false},{"option":"Bilateral nonhomogeneous infiltrations in both lungs with shifting of trachea on right side","bool":false},{"option":"Lateral x-ray of neck reveal \"thumb printing sign\"","bool":true},{"option":"Lateral x-ray of neck reveal \"steeple sign\"","bool":false}]},{"id":98,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 16-year-old tall male comes with sudden shortness of breath while he is playing football. His examination reveals, decreased air entry, hyper resonant percussion note with absent breath sound on the left side of the chest. Which of the following chest X-ray views should be requested to assess the lung pathology?","answers":[{"option":"Chest X-Ray P/A view","bool":false},{"option":"Expiratory P/A view","bool":true},{"option":"Later decubitus view","bool":false},{"option":"Superior A/P view","bool":false},{"option":"Inspiratory A/P view","bool":false}]},{"id":99,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 54-year-old man with a 20-pack year smoking history presents with shortness of breath. On physical examination, he is a thin and cyanotic man in moderate pulmonary distress. His chest shows an increased anteroposterior diameter, and breath sounds are faint with prolonged expiration. Which parameter is most likely found on the pulmonary function tests?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased FEV1: FVC ratio","bool":true},{"option":"Deceased total lung capacity","bool":false},{"option":"Increased FEV1: FVC ratio","bool":false},{"option":"Normal FEV1: FVC ratio","bool":false},{"option":"Increased forced vital capacity","bool":false}]},{"id":100,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Goodpasture syndrome is characterized by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Caseous necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Widespread infections","bool":false},{"option":"Hematomas","bool":false},{"option":"Granulomatous lesions","bool":false},{"option":"Nephritis and pneumonitis","bool":true}]},{"id":101,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is not true about pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Pleural effusion is a complication","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchodilators are drug of choice for treatment","bool":true},{"option":"It is an infectious disease","bool":false},{"option":"It is an acute respiratory illness","bool":false},{"option":"There is recently developed x-ray shadowing","bool":false}]},{"id":102,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the most common cause of lung abscess?","answers":[{"option":"Aspiration of infective material","bool":true},{"option":"Antecedent primary lung infection","bool":false},{"option":"Septic embolism","bool":false},{"option":"Neoplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Trauma","bool":false}]},{"id":103,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) is characterized by mucous gland hyperplasia and hypersecretion in bronchus?","answers":[{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumoconiosis","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic bronchitis","bool":true},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false}]},{"id":104,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A young girl complains of a nocturnal cough and shortness of breath, which disturbs her sleep. A diagnosis of bronchial asthma is made. The most important investigation to confirm this diagnosis is?","answers":[{"option":"Eosinophil count","bool":false},{"option":"Serum IgG level","bool":false},{"option":"X-Ray chest","bool":false},{"option":"Lung function test","bool":true},{"option":"Sputum examination","bool":false}]},{"id":105,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following most commonly results in violent asphyxia deaths?","answers":[{"option":"Iatrogenic asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Environmental asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Toxic asphyxia","bool":false},{"option":"Mechanical asphyxia","bool":true},{"option":"Pathological asphyxia","bool":false}]},{"id":106,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the causative organism for infection associated with ventilator tubings in the intensive care unit (ICU)?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumococcus","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":false},{"option":"Methicillin-resistant Staphylococcus aureus (MRSA)","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":true},{"option":"Moraxella catarrhalis","bool":false}]},{"id":107,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 54-year-old diabetic patient came with complaints of fever and cough for the past three days. Chest X-Ray shows a consolidation on the right upper chest. Which of the following is a bad prognostic sign in this condition?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory rate normal","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory rate < 15","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory rate > 30","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory rate < 30","bool":false},{"option":"Normal urea","bool":false}]},{"id":108,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A body has been found hanging from a tree. The ligature mark runs obliquely on the neck and ecchymosis adjacent to the ligature mark on the neck muscle is found. This is the feature of:","answers":[{"option":"Burking","bool":false},{"option":"Garroting","bool":false},{"option":"Postmortem hanging","bool":false},{"option":"Ante-mortem hanging","bool":true},{"option":"Strangulation","bool":false}]},{"id":109,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A medico-legal doctor was called by the state law authorities to perform an autopsy on a suspected poisoning case. A detailed study of the stomach and its contents is usually done by which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Opening along the lesser curvature","bool":false},{"option":"Opening by incision on its anterior wall","bool":false},{"option":"Opening along the greater curvature","bool":true},{"option":"Opening by a transverse incision","bool":false},{"option":"Can be opened by any side","bool":false}]},{"id":110,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 9-month-old child is brought to the clinic for the assessment of cough. On examination, his respiratory rate (R/R) is 52 breaths/minute with no chest retractions and no wheeze on auscultation. How will this child be classified according to Integrated Management of Newborn and Childhood Illnesses (IMNCI)?","answers":[{"option":"Cough and cold","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Very severe disease","bool":false},{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Severe pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":111,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 68-year-old diabetic came with a high-grade fever and a productive cough. There is a bronchial breath sound on the right upper chest. The treating physician suspected community-acquired pneumonia. The commonest cause of community-acquired pneumonia is:","answers":[{"option":"Streptococcus pneumoniae","bool":true},{"option":"Mycoplasma pneumoniae","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumocystis jiroveci","bool":false},{"option":"Staphylococcus aureus","bool":false},{"option":"Legionella pneumoniae","bool":false}]},{"id":112,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"In a putrefied body death resulted from drowning, diatoms are found in which of the following organs/viscera?","answers":[{"option":"Brain and bone marrow","bool":true},{"option":"Stomach and left lung","bool":false},{"option":"Ileum and under surface of liver","bool":false},{"option":"Gall bladder and liver","bool":false},{"option":"Hilum of right lung and right ear","bool":false}]},{"id":113,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Croup or acute laryngotracheitis is best defined as:","answers":[{"option":"Most patients with croup present between age group 5-7 years, present with fever , dry cough and expiratory stridor with drooling of saliva","bool":false},{"option":"Peak age of presentation is between 3 months to 5 years with history of high grade fever and sore throat for 1 day, patient looks toxic with respiratory distress , inspiratory strider with drooling of saliva","bool":false},{"option":"Peak age of presentation is between 3 months - 5 years with history of flu / cold in previous week , presents with inspiratory stridor, bark like or brassy cough","bool":true},{"option":"Peak age of presentation between 3-5 years, presents with expiratory stridor, severe respiratory distress and high grade fever with drooling of saliva","bool":false},{"option":"Peak age of presentation between 3-5 years, present with expiratory stridor , low grade fever and productive cough with history of viral flu in previous week","bool":false}]},{"id":114,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 37-year-old male develops sudden onset of right-sided chest pain associated with severe shortness of breath. There is no other symptom. He was well previously. On examination, he was in distress with a respiratory rate (R/R) of 26 per minute, blood pressure (BP) is 110/70 mmHg and the pulse is 108/min and febrile. Oxygen saturation is 92% and the trachea is central. Chest percussion on the right side has increased resonance with absent breath sound. What is the likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pneumothorax","bool":true},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Pericarditis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Pulmonary embolism","bool":false}]},{"id":115,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the most common type of bronchogenic carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchoalveolar carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":116,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Pulmonary tuberculosis is caused by which organism?","answers":[{"option":"Mycobacterium xenopi","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium diphtheriae","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium tuberculosis","bool":true},{"option":"Mycobacterium kansasii","bool":false},{"option":"Mycobacterium malmoense","bool":false}]},{"id":117,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Atopic asthma is caused by an immune response to environmental allergens. Which one of the following T-helper cells is involved in this exaggerated immune response?","answers":[{"option":"Combination of Th1 and Th17 response","bool":false},{"option":"Th1 response","bool":false},{"option":"Combination of Th1 and Th2 response","bool":false},{"option":"Th17 response","bool":false},{"option":"Th2 response","bool":true}]},{"id":118,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the causative organism of nosocomial (hospital-acquired) pneumonia?","answers":[{"option":"Legionella pneumophila","bool":false},{"option":"Moraxella catarrhalis","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumococcus","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudomonas aeruginosa","bool":true},{"option":"Klebsiella pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":119,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 34-year-old male is recently diagnosed with a case of pulmonary tuberculosis and is worried about his urine color since he started taking antitubercular therapy (ATT). Which of the following drug is considered to be the cause?","answers":[{"option":"Pyrazinamide (PZA)","bool":false},{"option":"Rifampicin","bool":true},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid (INH)","bool":false},{"option":"Thioacetazone","bool":false}]},{"id":120,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A neck infection in front of prevertebral fascia may extend:","answers":[{"option":"Into middle mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Into inferior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Through superior into anterior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Into superior mediastinum","bool":false},{"option":"Through superior into posterior mediastinum","bool":true}]},{"id":121,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 50-year-old man develops truncal obesity and bruising for 5 months. His blood pressure (BP) is 160/95 mmHg and his chest X-ray shows ill-defined 0.4 cm mass involving left hilum of the lung. Bronchial washing shows lymphocyte-like cells but somewhat larger. He was advised to stop smoking. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Non-Hodgkin lymphoma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Adenocarcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell carcinoma","bool":true}]},{"id":122,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"If pulmonary function test shows FEV1/FVC ratio is more than 0.70 with decreased total lung capacity (TLC), then the interpretation would be:","answers":[{"option":"Obstructive pattern","bool":false},{"option":"Non-specific reductions in FEV1 and FVC","bool":false},{"option":"Normal","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed pattern","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive pattern","bool":true}]},{"id":123,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 30-year-old female presents with complaints of chest pain, cough along with mucopurulent sputum, and high-grade fever for the last four days. On laboratory assessment, her chest X-ray shows patchy consolidation of both lungs. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Lobar pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Granulomatous disease of lungs","bool":false},{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchopneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Chronic pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":124,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Central proximal parts of acini formed by respiratory bronchioles are affected in:","answers":[{"option":"Centriacinar emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Distal acinar emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Panacinar emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Irregular emphysema","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial emphysema","bool":false}]},{"id":125,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Pneumothorax is most commonly associated with:","answers":[{"option":"Underlying malignancy","bool":false},{"option":"Asbestos exposure","bool":false},{"option":"Pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Sarcoidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema, asthma and tuberculosis","bool":true}]},{"id":126,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Tuberculosis granuloma of the lung exhibits characteristic features. Which of the following type of necrosis is seen in tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Coagulative","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaline","bool":false},{"option":"Caseous","bool":true},{"option":"Liquefactive","bool":false},{"option":"Fibrinoid","bool":false}]},{"id":127,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A patient has signs and symptoms of pneumoconiosis and having asbestosis. Which of the following statement is correct regarding asbestos-related illness?","answers":[{"option":"The most common finding with asbestos exposure is pleural plaques","bool":true},{"option":"Pleural plaques develop most commonly in the apices of the lung pleura","bool":false},{"option":"The most common finding with asbestos exposure is asbestos bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural plaques contain asbestos bodies","bool":false},{"option":"Pleural effusions are a common occurrence in asbestos related disease","bool":false}]},{"id":128,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A patient with tuberculosis is started on isoniazid (INH) as part of a multidrug regimen. The physician also starts therapy with vitamin B6 at the same time. Which of the following is the main reason for giving the vitamin B6 prophylactically?","answers":[{"option":"Prevents some adverse effects of INH therapy","bool":true},{"option":"Inhibits metabolism of INH","bool":false},{"option":"Is a cofactor required for activation of INH","bool":false},{"option":"Facilitates INH renal excretion","bool":false},{"option":"Potentiates the antitubercular activity of the INH","bool":false}]},{"id":129,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"The human organ which was first examined by nuclear medicine studies was:","answers":[{"option":"Pancreas","bool":false},{"option":"Thyroid","bool":true},{"option":"Brain","bool":false},{"option":"Bone","bool":false},{"option":"Heart","bool":false}]},{"id":130,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 55-year-old patient suffering from persistent dry cough for the last 2-months due to unknown reasons wants to get a drug without having constipating effects. Which of the following would you prescribe?","answers":[{"option":"Codeine","bool":false},{"option":"Pholcodine","bool":false},{"option":"Hydrocodone","bool":false},{"option":"Dextromethorphan","bool":true},{"option":"Physostigmine","bool":false}]},{"id":131,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"What is the most important mechanism of action of corticosteroids in asthma?","answers":[{"option":"Direct relaxation of air way smooth muscle","bool":false},{"option":"Decrease in secretion of mucus that occurs in response to vagal activity","bool":false},{"option":"Inhibition of the lymphocytic eosinophilic mucosal inflammation of asthmatic airway","bool":true},{"option":"Increase in ciliary activity","bool":false},{"option":"Cause contraction of engorged vessels in bronchial mucosa","bool":false}]},{"id":132,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following agents can reverse the peripheral neuropathy caused by isoniazid?","answers":[{"option":"Folate","bool":false},{"option":"Niacin","bool":false},{"option":"Ascorbic acid","bool":false},{"option":"Thiamine","bool":false},{"option":"Pyridoxine","bool":true}]},{"id":133,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is the correct interpretation of arterial blood gases when pH is 7.30, PCO2 is 24 mmHg and HCO3 is 15 mmol/dL?","answers":[{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Normal","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false}]},{"id":134,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 25-year-old male presents with a one-week history of cough and fever. On examination, he has signs of consolidation. Which of the following signs is more specific for consolidation?","answers":[{"option":"Decreased chest movement on affected side","bool":false},{"option":"Fine crepitation","bool":false},{"option":"Mediastinal shifting","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchial breathing","bool":false},{"option":"Dull percussion note","bool":true}]},{"id":135,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is an important microscopical feature of acute respiratory distress syndrome (ARDS)?","answers":[{"option":"Diffuse alveolar damage","bool":true},{"option":"Diffuse bronchiolar damage","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse septal fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse interstitial fibrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Diffuse bronchoalveolar damage","bool":false}]},{"id":136,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Host risk factors for the development of chronic obstructive pulmonary disease (COPD) include which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Outdoor and indoor air pollution","bool":false},{"option":"Low birth weight","bool":false},{"option":"Tobacco smoke","bool":false},{"option":"Biomass solid fuel fires","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha-1 anti-protease deficiency","bool":true}]},{"id":137,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following drugs exerts its antimycobacterial activity by interfering with the synthesis of mycolic acid, which are the essential components of mycobacterial cell walls?","answers":[{"option":"Streptomycin","bool":false},{"option":"Ethambutol","bool":false},{"option":"Pyrazinamide","bool":false},{"option":"Isoniazid","bool":true},{"option":"Rifampin","bool":false}]},{"id":138,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 64-year-old patient with hypertension is admitted with uncontrolled blood pressure. After 6 days of admission, he develops a high-grade fever and a productive cough with green sputum. What is the most likely cause of his current problem?","answers":[{"option":"Hospital acquired pneumonia","bool":true},{"option":"Viral pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Cryptogenic organized pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Atypical pneumonia","bool":false},{"option":"Community acquired pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":139,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which one of the following is a prophylactic agent used in cases of bronchial asthma that stabilizes mast cells?","answers":[{"option":"Metaproterenol","bool":false},{"option":"Ipratropium bromide","bool":false},{"option":"Cromolyn","bool":true},{"option":"Aminophylline","bool":false},{"option":"Terbutaline","bool":false}]},{"id":140,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which one of the following is the main cause of resistance of mycobacteria to rifampin?","answers":[{"option":"Mutation preventing the bindings of rifampin to RNA polymerase","bool":true},{"option":"Mutation resulting in over expression of RNA polymerase","bool":false},{"option":"Increased efflux of rifampin from the bacterial cell by an active pump","bool":false},{"option":"Decreased penetration of rifampin into the bacterial cell","bool":false},{"option":"Increased formation of a enzyme that inactivate rifampin","bool":false}]},{"id":141,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 21-year-old female came with a dry cough and shortness of breath for 6 months. For the past week, she is also having nocturnal symptoms. Her treating physician advised a pulmonary function test. \r\nInterpret the following pulmonary function test of this lady: FEV1=50% of predicted, FEV1/FVC=60%, and FVC=82% of predicted.","answers":[{"option":"Poor effort","bool":false},{"option":"Mixed pattern","bool":false},{"option":"Normal pulmonary function test (PFT)","bool":false},{"option":"Restrictive pattern","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive pattern","bool":true}]},{"id":142,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following diseases involve the destruction of the terminal part of the bronchial tree?","answers":[{"option":"Asthma","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchiolitis","bool":false},{"option":"Emphysema","bool":true},{"option":"Atelectasis","bool":false},{"option":"Bronchitis","bool":false}]},{"id":143,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which type of emphysema involves proximal airway damage?","answers":[{"option":"Centrilobular","bool":true},{"option":"Paraseptal","bool":false},{"option":"Panacinar","bool":false},{"option":"Distal acinar","bool":false},{"option":"None of these","bool":false}]},{"id":144,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which type of cancer gives the best response to chemotherapy?","answers":[{"option":"Non-carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Small cell lung carcinoma","bool":true},{"option":"Squamous cell carcinoma","bool":false},{"option":"Carcinoid tumor","bool":false},{"option":"Large cell carcinoma","bool":false}]},{"id":145,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following correctly describes the findings of squamous cell carcinoma?","answers":[{"option":"Clara cells","bool":false},{"option":"Chromogranin positive cells","bool":false},{"option":"Keratin pearls","bool":true},{"option":"Eosinophillic stain","bool":false},{"option":"Kulchitsky cells","bool":false}]},{"id":146,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"Which of the following is not associated with tuberculosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cavitary fibrous lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Ghon complex","bool":false},{"option":"Advanced fibrous lesion","bool":false},{"option":"Lung abscess","bool":true},{"option":"Bronchogenic pneumonia","bool":false}]},{"id":147,"info":"3rd-year/respiratory/2020","question":"A 34-year-old male presents with a history of altered consciousness for one day. Arterial blood gas (ABG) results show pH 7.31, PCO2 = 24 mmHg, HCO3 = 15 mmol/L. Which of the following is the most likely condition?","answers":[{"option":"Respiratory alkalosis","bool":false},{"option":"Normal","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic acidosis","bool":true},{"option":"Respiratory acidosis","bool":false},{"option":"Metabolic alkalosis","bool":false}]}]
export default arr